Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals PE.030
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals
1873-2017
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Sweezy, Martha
Baskin, Alex
PE.030
35.25 Linear Feet in 33 record cartons, 3 manuscript boxes, and 5 shared boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals (1873-2017), an artificial collection of vertical files, was accumulated gradually over the years as staff set aside ephemera that was relevant to Tamiment Library's collecting focus but did not belong in discreet collections. This collection consists of biographies, collections of writings, event programs and invitations, promotional materials, flyers, clippings, leaflets, manifestoes, pamphlets, press releases, and other printed ephemera created by or related to individuals connected with the labor movement, trade unionism, radical politics, feminism, civil rights, and other movements.
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical Note
The Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of printed ephemera gradually over the years through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, trade unions and other organizations, and through exchanges with other special library collections via the Collectors' Network, which was organized by Russell Benedict at the University of Nevada in the 1970s and promoted through his newsletter Top Secret. Tamiment Library staff added materials to this collection on a regular basis.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Individuals (1873-2017) is composed of printed ephemera related to the primary collecting areas of the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives: Leftist politics and Labor history. This collection includes files created by or related to people who were a part of or of interest to members of the political Left in the United States. This collection includes files created by or related to people who were of a part of or of interest to members of the political Left in the United States, including politicians and political leaders, labor leaders, unionists, activists, and public intellectuals. This collection contains files on Angela Davis, Irving Howe, Vito Marcantonio, Paul Robeson, Ethel and Julius Rosenberg, I.F. Stone, and others.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into 26 series; one for each letter of the alphabet. Files are arranged alphabetically by file title.
Series are arranged alphabetically.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Various materials were found in the repository and added to this collection. The accession numbers associated with this material are: 2014.030, 2014.044, 2014.052, 2014.056, 2014.075, 2018.032, and NPA.2001.075.
Alex Baskin donated Mikhail Bakunin lithographs in 1990. The accession number associated with this gift is 2018.035.
Martha Sweezy donated the papers of Paul Sweezy in 2004. There is no accession record associated with this gift.
In 2025, unprocessed materials from accession 2019.056, which is associated with Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects (PE 029), were transferred to this collection.
Related Materials
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations (PE 036)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects (PE 029)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Trade Unions (PE 001)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection of Oversized Material (PE 040)
New Left -- United States.; Labor movement.; Communists.; Communism.; Reprints.; Student movements -- United States.; Anarchists -- United States.; Fliers (printed matter); Antinuclear movement -- United States.; Anti-war demonstrations.; Civil rights.; Radicalism -- United States.; Political campaigns -- New York (State) -- New York.; Women's rights.; Peace movements -- United States.; Broadsides (notices); Anarchism -- United States.; Pamphlets.; Gay liberation movement -- United States.; Feminists -- United States.; Feminism -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Demonstrations -- United States.; Leaflets (printed works); Printed ephemera.; Socialists -- United States.; Reports.; Sweezy, Martha; Baskin, Alex
- A, 1881-2006; 1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript box
  - Abbott, Konrad Bercovici, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Lyman, undated (Box 1)
  - Abelson, Evelyn, 1926-2008, undated (Box 1)
  - Abramovitch, Raphael R., 1950 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Charles, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Irving S., 1980 (Box 1)
  - Abt, John J., 1975-1991 (Box 1)
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Ackelsberg, Martha A., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Samuel, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Addams, Jane, 1917 (Box 1)
  - Addison, Chester, undated (Box 1)
  - Adler, Irvin, 1993, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Agee, Philip, undated (Box 1)
  - Albizu Campos, Pedro, 1891-1965, circa 1963 (Box 1)
  - Aldred, Guy A., 1940 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Jim, circa 2000 (Box 1)
  - Altgeld, John Peter, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Ameringer, Oscar, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Amidon, Beulah, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Amter, Israel, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Kirk, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Mary, undated (Box 1)
  - Andreas, Bert, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, John Bertram, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Angell, Norman, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Anneke, Mathilde Franziska Giesler, undated (Box 1)
  - Antonini, Luigi, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Aptheker, Herbert, 1915-2003, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Ashe, Thomas, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Ashleigh, Charles, undated (Box 1)
  - Ashley, Jessie, 1919 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Ti Grace, undated (Box 1)
  - Auer, Ignaz, 1907 (Box 1)
  - Aveling, Edward Bibbins, undated (Box 1)
  - Aveling, Eleanor Marx, 1855-1898, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Avineri, Shlomo, undated (Box 1)
  - Avrich, Paul, 2006 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod, Pavel, 1881 (Box 1)
  - Ayoub, Elias, 1979 (Box 1)
- B, 1895-2008; 5.25 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes, and 1 shared oversize box
  - Baar, K. Kevyne, 2007 (Box 1)
  - Baarslag, Karl, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Babeuf, Gracchus, 1760-1797, 1895 (Box 1)
  - Bachrach, Marion, undated (Box 1)
  - Bailin, Israel Ber, 1883-1961 (Box 1)
  - Baitalsky, Mikhail, undated (Box 1)
  - Baker, Arthur Brooks, undated (Box 1)
  - Baker, Charles, circa 1917 (Box 1)
  - Baker, Ella, 1903-1986, 1980- (Box 1)
  - Bakunin, Mikhail Aleksandrovich, 1814-1876, undated (Box 1, Box Shared Tamiment 009, Folder 13)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Balch, Emily Greene, 1867-1961, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Evelyn Preston, 1898?-1962 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, James, 1924-1987, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981, 1918 (Box 1)
  - Banneker, Benjamin, undated (Box 1)
  - Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-, 1960, undated (Box 1, Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Barabo, Frank, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Baraldini, Silvia, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Baran, Paul A., undated (Box 1)
  - Barbash, Jack, circa 1947 (Box 1)
  - Barenblatt, Lloyd, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Barjonet, André, circa 1959 (Box 1)
  - Barker, Tom, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Barkin, Solomon, 1907-, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Barloon, Marvin J., undated (Box 1)
  - Barnard, Henry H., 1976 (Box 1)
  - Barondess, Benjamin, b. 1891, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Baronian, Harry, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Barr, Jessica, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Barzun, Jacques, 1907-, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Basel, Amos S., undated (Box 1)
  - Baskin, Joseph, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Baxter, W. F., 1937 (Box 1)
  - Beal, Fred Erwin, 1896-1954, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Bean, Louis H. (Louis Hyman), 1896-1994, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Beard, Charles Austin, 1874-1948, 1922 (Box 1)
  - Bebel, August, 1840-1913, 1892 (Box 1)
  - Beck, Burt, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Beck, Carl, 1914 (Box 1)
  - Beck, Dave, 1894-1993, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Beck, Julian, 1925-1985 (Box 1)
  - Beckerman, Abraham, circa 1917 (Box 1)
  - Bedacht, Max, 1883-1972 (Box 1)
  - Bedford-Jones, Nancy, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Beffel, John Nicholas, 1973 (Box 1)
  - Beichman, Arnold, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Belevich, E., 1940 (Box 1)
  - Belfrage, Cedric, 1904-, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Belgrado, Pedrini, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Daniel, circa 1949 (Box 1)
  - Bell, Fred, undated (Box 1)
  - Bellamy, Edward, 1897 (Box 1)
  - Bellanca, Dorothy, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Belsky, Joseph, circa 1940 (Box 1)
  - Belsky, Louis, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1948, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Benét, Stephen Vincent, 1898-1943, undated (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Fay, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Benson, Allan L., 1914 (Box 1)
  - Benson, H. W., 1959 (Box 1)
  - Benson, Revella, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Bent, Silas, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Ben-Yitchak, Mier, circa 1970 (Box 1)
  - Bercovici, Konrad, 1882-1961 (Box 1)
  - Berenberg, David P., 1934 (Box 1)
  - Berenson, Lori, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Beria, Lavrenti, undated (Box 1)
  - Bergel, Lienhard, 1905-1987, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Berger, Victor L., 1860-1929, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936, 1902 (Box 2)
  - Berkman, Brenda, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Berland, Oscar, 1962 (Box 2)
  - Berle, Adolf Augustus, 1895-1971, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Berman, Louise Bransten, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Berman, Naomi, circa 1986 (Box 2)
  - Berman, Nathan, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Bernal, J. D. (John Desmond), 1901-, undated (Box 2)
  - Bernard, John T., circa 1977 (Box 2)
  - Bernard, Theo, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Bernays, Edward L., 1891-1995, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Berndt, I.A., 1917 (Box 2)
  - Bernhardt, Debra E. I, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Bernhardt, Debra E. II, 2001 (Box 2, Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Bernstein, Samuel, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Berrigan, Daniel, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Berrigan, Phillip, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Bert, Erik, 1904-1981, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Berthoff, Rowland, 1921-, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Besant, Annie Wood, 1847-1933, undated (Box 2)
  - Bethune, Norman, Dr., undated (Box 2)
  - Bettelheim, Bruno, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Biberman, Edward, 2008 (Box 2)
  - Bienstock, Herbert, 1922-, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Biermann, Wolf, 1936-, undated (Box 2)
  - Bigelow, Herbert S. (Herbert Seely), b. 1870, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Bikel, Theodore, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Bilbo, Theodore Gilmore, 1877-1947, undated (Box 2)
  - Billings, Warren K., 1893-1972, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Bingham, Stephen, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Bird, Ira, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Birkhead, L. M. (Leon Milton), 1885-1954, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Bittelman, Alex, 1890-1982, circa 1938 (Box 2)
  - Black, Hugo LaFayette, 1886-1971, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Black, Isabella, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Blackston, Johnnie Tillmon, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Blair, Fred, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Blanco, Hugo, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Blank, Geoffrey, 2006 (Box 2)
  - Blanqui, Louis Auguste, 1805-1881, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Blatch, Harriot Stanton, 1856-1940, undated (Box 2)
  - Blauvelt, Mildred, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Bleeker, Sylvia, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Bliumin, I. G. (Izrail Grigorevich), 1897-1959, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Blitzstein, Marc, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Bloch, Herman D., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Bloch, Maurice, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Bloor, Ella Reeve, 1862-1951, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Blossom, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), b. 1878, 1974 (Box 2)
  - Blotch, Anna, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Blum, Emanuel, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Boas, Ernst P. (Ernst Philip), 1891-1955, undated (Box 2)
  - Boggs, James, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Bohn, Frank, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Bohn, Wm. E. (William Edward), b. 1877, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Bohr, Niels, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Bond, Julian, 1940-, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Boni, Albert, 1892-1981, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Bookchin, Murray, 1921-2006, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Bool, Henry, undated (Box 2)
  - Booth, William, 1829-1912, 1890 (Box 2)
  - Borghi, Armando, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Borochov, Ber, 1881-1917, undated (Box 2)
  - Borodin, Mikhail Markovich, 1884-1951, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Borosini, Victor Von, undated (Box 2)
  - Boudin, Leonard B., 1948 (Box 2)
  - Boudin, Louis B. (Louis Boudianoff), 1874-1952 I, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Boudin, Louis B. (Louis Boudianoff), 1874-1952 II, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Bourgina, Anna M., 1946 (Box 2)
  - Bourne, Randolph Silliman, 1886-1918, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Bovshover, Joseph, 1873-1915, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Bowman, LeRoy, 1887-1971, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Frederick Sumner, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Boyd, Malcolm, 1923-, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Boyle, William Anthony, 1904-1985, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Braden, Carl, 1914-1975, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Bradlaugh, Charles, 1833-1891, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Bradley, Lyman, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1878-1962 (Box 3)
  - Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941, 1915 (Box 3)
  - Brandes, Georg, undated (Box 3)
  - Brandt, Willy, 1913-1992, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Branstetter, Otto, undated (Box 3)
  - Braunthal, Alfred, undated (Box 3)
  - Braverman, Harry, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Brecht, Bertolt I, 1961 (Box 3, Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Brecht, Bertolt II, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Breitman, George, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Brenton, Arthur, 1924 (Box 3)
  - Bresci, Gaetano, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Bricker, John W. (John William), 1893-1986, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Harry I, 1939- (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Harry II, 1939- (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Harry III, 1939- (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Harry IV, 1939- (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Harry V, 1939- (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Harry: Citizens Victory Committee, 1942-1945, undated (Box 3)
  - Bridges, Styles, 1898-1961, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Brieux, Eugène, 1858-1932, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Briggs, Cyril V. (Cyril Valentine), 1888-1966, 1931 (Box 3)
  - Brisben, John Quinn, 1934-, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Brissenden, Paul F. (Paul Frederick), 1885-1974, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Brodine, Karen, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Brodine, Virginia, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Brook, Michael, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Gwendolyn, 1917-2000, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Brooks, John Graham, circa 1895 (Box 3)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Brophy, John, 1883-1963, 1922 (Box 3)
  - Brothers, Thomas, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Brouckère, Louis de, 1870-1951, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Broun, Heywood, 1888-1939, 1930 (Box 3)
  - Browder, Earl, 1891-1973 I, 1936-1950 (Box 3, Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Browder, Earl, 1891-1973 II, 1936- (Box 3)
  - Brown, Bob, 1886-1959, undated (Box 3)
  - Brown, Emily Clark, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Brown, H. LaRue, circa 1913 (Box 4)
  - Brown, Harry Gunnison, 1880-, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Brown, Irving, 1911-, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Brown, John, 1800-1859, 1951 (Box 4)
  - Brown, Judith, undated (Box 4)
  - Brown, Lloyd L. (Lloyd Louis), 1913-, 1975 (Box 4)
  - Brown, Ronald Allen, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Browne, Henry, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Brownson, Josephine, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Brownson, Orestes Augustus, 1803-1876, 1913 (Box 4)
  - Bruno, Giordano, 1548-1600, 1889 (Box 4)
  - Bryan, Helen, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Bryant, Alice Franklin, 1962-1966 (Box 4)
  - Bucar, Annabelle, 1949 (Box 4)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Buck, Tim, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Buckley, Louis F., 1948 (Box 4)
  - Budenz, Louis F. (Louis Francis), 1891-1972, 1935 (Box 4)
  - Bukharin, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1888-1938, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Burchett, Wilfred G., 1911-1983, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Burke, John P., 1941 (Box 4)
  - Burke, Robert, undated (Box 4)
  - Burliuk, David, 1882-1967, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Burnham, Dorothy (Dorothy C.), 1990 (Box 4)
  - Burnham, James, 1905-1987 (Box 4)
  - Burns, John, 1888 (Box 4)
  - Burrows, Herbert, 1908 (Box 4)
  - Butler, Smedley D. (Smedley Darlington), 1881-1940, 1935 (Box 4)
- C, 1907-2002; 3 Linear Feet in 2 record cartons and 2 manuscript boxes
  - Cacchione, Peter V., 1947 (Box 4)
  - Cahan, Abraham, 1860-1951, 1926 (Box 4)
  - Caldicott, Helen, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Calese, Bob, undated (Box 4)
  - Calomiris, Angela, undated (Box 4)
  - Cannon, James Patrick, 1890-1974, 1934 (Box 4, Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Capozzi, Louis, 1988 (Box 4)
  - Carey, Philip A., 1960 (Box 4)
  - Carey, Ronald, 1992 (Box 4)
  - Carey, Thomas, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Carlson, John Roy, 1909-, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Carmichael, Stokely, 1966-1975 (Box 4)
  - Carr, Charlotte E., 1956 (Box 4)
  - Carthan, Eddie, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Casselman, P.H., 1947 (Box 4)
  - Castro, Fidel, 1926-, 1959-1989 (Box 4, Box 34, Folder 6, Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Chafee, Zechariah, 1885-1957, 1919 (Box 4)
  - Chagin, B. A. (Boris Aleksandrovich), 1899-, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Challiss, Raymond, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Chanin, N., d.1965 (Box 4)
  - Chaplin, Charlie, 1889-1977, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Chaplin, Ralph, 1887-1961 (Box 4)
  - Chase, Elba, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Chase, Stuart, 1888-1985, undated (Box 4)
  - Chavez, Cesar, 1927-1993, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Chernin, Rose, undated (Box 4)
  - Chernov, V. M. (Viktor Mikhailovich), 1873-1952, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Chester, Harry, 1994 (Box 4)
  - Cheyney, Ralph, 1896-1941, 1945 (Box 4)
  - Chisholm, Shirley, 1924-2005, circa 1972 (Box 4)
  - Chodorov, Frank, 1887-1966 (Box 4)
  - Chomsky, Noam, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Christiani, Enus, undated (Box 4)
  - Christie, Stewart, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Christoffel, Harold, undated (Box 4)
  - Chu, Valentin, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Cienfuegos, Camilo, 1962 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Cipriani, Amilcare, 1843-1918, 1912 (Box 4)
  - Cisler, Lucinda, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Citron, Casper, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Claessens, August, 1885-1954, 1909 (Box 4)
  - Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon), 1897-1978, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Cleage, Albert B. (Cleage for Council), undated (Box 4)
  - Cleaver, Eldridge, 1935-1998, 1968, undated (Box 4, Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Cleghorn, Sarah Norcliffe, 1876-1959 (Box 4)
  - Clement, Travers, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Cliff, Tony, 1917-, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Climenko, Leon, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Clinton, Bill, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Cobden, Richard, 1804-1865, undated (Box 4)
  - Cogen, Charles, 1903-, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Joseph E., 1907 (Box 4)
  - Cohn-Bendit, Daniel, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Coit, Eleanor G., 1939 (Box 4)
  - Coldwell, Joseph M., undated (Box 4)
  - Cole, David L. (David Lawrence), 1902-1978, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Cole, G. D. H. (George Douglas Howard), 1889-1959, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Cole, Kathleen, undated (Box 4)
  - Cole, Lester, 1904-1985 (Box 4)
  - Cole, Nathan A., undated (Box 5)
  - Coleman, McAlister, 1889-, 1933 (Box 5)
  - Collinet, Michel, 1961 (Box 5)
  - Colon, Jesus, 1974 (Box 5)
  - Colton, Peter, circa 1953 (Box 5)
  - Commager, Henry Steele, 1902-1998, undated (Box 5)
  - Commons, John Rogers, 1862-1945, 1911 (Box 5)
  - Conger-Kaneko, Josephine, circa 1912 (Box 5)
  - Connolly, James, 1868-1916, 1934-1949 (Box 5)
  - Conrad, Earl, circa 1952 (Box 5)
  - Cook, Alice Hanson, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Cook, Charles J., undated (Box 5)
  - Cook, Walter, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Cooper, Jake, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Corey, Lewis, circa 1914 (Box 5)
  - Cornish, Edwin R., undated (Box 5)
  - Corsi, Edward, 1896-1965 (Box 5)
  - Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Coughlin, Charles E. (Charles Edward), 1891-1979, undated (Box 5)
  - Coughlin, Howard, 1984 (Box 5)
  - Coughlin, Michael, 2002 (Box 5)
  - Coulter, John Lee, 1881-1959, 1909 (Box 5)
  - Council, James, undated (Box 5)
  - Counts, George S. (George Sylvester), 1889-1974, 1952 (Box 5)
  - Cournos, John, 1881-1966, undated (Box 5)
  - Cox, Archibald, 1912-2004, 1950 (Box 5)
  - Craven, Harry J. B., 1966 (Box 5)
  - Croan, Melvin, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Crocker, Lester G., 1962 (Box 5)
  - Crockett, George W., 1997 (Box 5)
  - Cronin, John F. (John Francis), 1908-, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Crook, Wilfrid Harris, b. 1888, 1931 (Box 5)
  - Crosby, Ernest Howard, 1856-1907, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Crossman, R. H. S. (Richard Howard Stafford), 1907-1974, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Crosswaith, Frank Rudolph, 1892-1965, 1938 (Box 5)
  - Cruz, Eduardo, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Curran, Joseph, 1963 (Box 5)
  - Curtis, Mark, 1988 (Box 5)
  - Curtiss, Charles, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Cushing, Gordon G., circa 1951 (Box 5)
- D, 1880-2014; 3.75 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 oversize shared box
  - Da Silva, Howard, 1909-1986 (Box 5)
  - Dan, F. (Fedor), 1871-1947, circa 1935 (Box 5)
  - Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1881-1950, undated (Box 5)
  - D'Andrea, Virgilia, 1890-1933, 2004 (Box 5)
  - Danish, Max D., 1964 (Box 5)
  - Darrow, Clarence, 1857-1938, 1914 (Box 5)
  - Dave, Victor, 1907 (Box 5)
  - David, Henry, 1907-, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Davidman, Joy, 1949 (Box 5)
  - Davis, Angela Y. (Angela Yvonne), 1944-, 1969-2014 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Davis, Angela Y. (Angela Yvonne), 1944- :Defense Fund/ Committees, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
  - Davis, Benjamin J. (Benjamin Jefferson), 1903-1964, 1945-1967 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Davis, Ossie, 1968-1980 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Davis, Troy Anthony, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Day, Dorothy, 1897-1980, 1938 (Box 5)
  - De Cleyre, Voltairine, 1866-1912 (Box 5)
  - De Gregory, Hugo, 1960 (Box 5)
  - De Leon, Daniel, 1852-1914, 1899 (Box 5)
  - De Leon, Solon, 1883-, 1904 (Box 5)
  - Deakin, Arthur, 1890-1955 (Box 5)
  - Dean, Vera Micheles, 1947 (Box 5)
  - DeBoer, Harry, 1992 (Box 5)
  - Debord, Guy, 1931-, 1995 (Box 5)
  - Debouzy, Marianne, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Debray, Régis, 1967 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926 I, 1908 (Box 5)
  - Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926 II, 1961-1976 (Box 5, Box 34, Folder 14, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 26)
  - Degras, Jane, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Dell, Floyd, 1887-1969 (Box 6)
  - Dellinger, David T., 1915-2004, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Dellums, Ronald V., 1935-, 1984 (Box 6)
  - DeMaio, Ernest, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Deming, Barbara, 1917-1984, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Denitch, Bogdan Denis, undated (Box 6)
  - Dennett, Mary Ware, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Dennis, Eugene, 1905-, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Dennis, Peggy, 1976 (Box 6)
  - DeRorre, Katie, 1961 (Box 6)
  - Despres, Leon M., 1939 (Box 6)
  - Desser, Abraham A., 1936 (Box 6)
  - Deutsch, Albert, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Deutsch, Julius, 1934 (Box 6)
  - Dewey, John, 1859-1952, 1928, 1977 (Box 6)
  - Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971, circa 1937 (Box 6)
  - Diamond, Freda, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Dies, Martin, 1900-1972, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Dimitrov, Georgi, 1882-1949, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Dinkins, David, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Disston, Frank, 1880-1937 (Box 6)
  - Ditchek, David N., 1920 (Box 6)
  - DiVittorio, Giuseppe, 1892-1957, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Dixon, Marlene, 1936-, undated (Box 6)
  - Djilas, Milovan, 1911-1995, 1948 (Box 6)
  - Dobbs, Farrell, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Dodd, Bella V., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Dodge, Martin, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Doherty, Joseph Patrick, 1955-, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Dolgoff, Sam, 1902-, 1989 (Box 6)
  - Dombrowski, James A. (James Anderson), 1897-1983, undated (Box 6)
  - Dominique, Jean (Committee to Support), undated (Box 6)
  - Donahue, Thomas R., 1982 (Box 6)
  - Dorr, Rheta Childe, 1866-1948, 1909 (Box 6)
  - Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970, circa 1948 (Box 6)
  - Douai, Adolf, 1819-1888 (Box 6)
  - Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976, 1918 (Box 6)
  - Doumoulin, Georges, undated (Box 6)
  - Dowd, Ray, undated (Box 6)
  - Doyle, Joe, 1978 (Box 6)
  - Draper, Hal, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1912-2006, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Dreier, Mary E. (Mary Elisabeth), 1875-1963, 1921 (Box 6)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945, 1931 (Box 6)
  - Dridzo, Solomon Abramovich, 1921 (Box 6)
  - Driscoll, Robert Bruce, undated (Box 6)
  - Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963, 1946-1978 (Box 6, Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Duclos, Jacques, 1896-1975, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Dunayevskaya, Raya, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Duncan, Isadora, undated (Box 6)